Ben Cole - Web development + digital marketing

Quick profile

I have recently completed a Full-Stack Web Developer Bootcamp at the University of Adelaide, (6 months Jan - Jul 2020), which has given me a good working knowledge of the following web technologies - Javascript ES6, MongoDB, Express Server, React and Node, (M.E.R.N. stack) along with associated databases, libraries and frameworks like MYSQL, Sequelize, Handlebars, Mongoose, Moment.js, Axios, Lodash and version control with GitHub.

In addition to web development, I have experience as a Product Owner for a UK based SaaS marketing platform. I have led agile teams comprised of external agencies, account managers, designers and developers through phases of change and innovation to deliver better, leaner, digital services that boost company performance.

I also have 15 years industry experience in digital marketing and senior client handling for brands like Nike, Sainsbury's, Marks & Spencer, Airbnb, Aldermore Bank, American Express, Capital One, Groupon, Orbitz Worldwide, ebookers.

Skills and attributes

- Junior M.E.R.N. stack developer and Adelaide University Bootcamp graduate 2020
- Design graduate with knowledge of service design and user-centred design thinking
- UI designer who can create polished graphic interfaces using Google Material Design principles
- Solid consultancy and client handling skills with the ability to reason and influence
- Skilled at turning business requirements into software
- Advanced knowledge of Photoshop and Illustrator
- Strong project management skills
- Self-directed with the ability to learn new technologies
- Strong team player

Experience

Senior Service Designer - Livework (Contract)

Service Design Consultancy | Jun 2019 - Oct 2019 | www.liveworkstudio.com

Part of a multi-disciplinary team designing new digital services for Uniphar medical distribution. We conducted ethnographic interviews with Patients and Healthcare Professionals to uncover new opportunities to service patients. I worked in the design team to unpack interview insights, create user journeys and design 4 new service propositions which were presented to Uniphar's innovation team.

Head of Business Development - Livework (Contract)

Service Design Consultancy | Jun 2018 - Mar 2019 | www.liveworkstudio.com

Helping Livework to explore new strategies and channels for developing business in a competitive market place for service design consultancy. I worked with the Founder to help Livework develop an outside-in view of his business. I wrote copy and developed marketing collateral that communicated the benefits of using service design to de-risk innovation spend. The work resulted in meetings, pitches and new business with Tesco Bank, Aldermore Bank, Barclays, TSB and Morgan Stanley.

Founder / Chief Operating Officer - Scale Digital

Specialist Affiliate Marketing Agency | Feb 2017 - May 2018 (Exited) | www.scaledigital.co

Set up and ran a specialist affiliate marketing agency helping clients to optimise, cashback, voucher code, price comparison, content, re-targeting, display prospecting and more. I acted as the strategic lead for our top accounts including Airbnb, CurrencyFair and SteelSeries. Scale Digital offers clients access to a highly-skilled team of digital marketers with experience of running international affiliate programs for some of Europe's largest online retailers including Nike, American Express, Capital One, Mothercare, Airbnb, etc.

Chief Development Officer - Webgains (Ad Pepper Media PLC)

International Affiliate Marketing Agency | Jul 2014 - Jan 2017 | www.webgains.com

Webgains is a digital marketing platform accessed by 25,000+ clients in 18 markets, turning over €50m annually. I was the Product Owner with strategic responsibility for developing the platform. I engaged Service Designers and UX Consultants to interview our stakeholders. We redesigned the user experience taking a 'mobile first' approach and building a rich technical roadmap of features which were built by an in-house team of 11 Software Developers.

Commercial Director - Webgains (Ad Pepper Media PLC)

International Affiliate Marketing Agency | Dec 2012 - Jun 2014 | www.webgains.com

Responsible for building strategic partnerships with Europe's biggest marketing affiliates - understanding how their technology propositions would serve our customers and then helping them to sell to our client base. Partners included Criteo, NMPi, Vouchercodes.co.uk, Myvouchercodes, Quidco, Groupon, Moneysupermarket, Comparethemarket, Target.de, Studentbeans....

Business Development Director - Alchemy Social (Experian PLC)

Facebook Marketing | Jun 2011 - Nov 2012 | www.experian.co.uk/business/marketing

Strategic sales consultancy for a top performing Facebook API partner. I sold Software as a Service, (SaaS) and Managed Service products to clients in Retail, Finance and Gaming. For brands that wanted to map their consumer data into social media, Alchemy Social was their 1st choice; for agencies that wanted to license ad optimisation technology, Alchemy Social offered first class support and best practice knowledge of Facebook marketing through our delivery teams.

Business Development Director - TBG Digital (acquired by Sprinklr 2016)

Facebook Marketing | Feb 2010 - May 2011 | www.sprinklr.com

TBG was the #1 billing Facebook API advertising partner globally. I worked with clients and the Facebook marketing teams in Dublin to devise marketing strategies that would deliver maximum return on ad spend for Capital One, Marks and Spencer, Sainsburys etc.

Head of Client Sales - TradeDoubler International

Affiliate Marketing | Jun 2008 - Jan 2010 | www.tradedoubler.com

Leading a team of five, selling Affiliate, Display, Paid Search, SEO, Pay-Per-Call and SaaS directly to Europe's leading online advertisers and household brand names. Helping clients to understand why TradeDoubler could offer them the support they needed to achieve their aggressive sales targets. Successful pitches included GAP (International SEM), Halfords, British Gas, EDF Energy etc.

Sales Manager - TradeDoubler International

Affiliate Marketing | Jan 2007 - Jun 2008 | www.tradedoubler.com

Part of the team that delivered the 2009 target by securing affiliate business from Vodafone, Mothercare ELC, The AA, Universal Music etc.

Business Advisor - Prevista

Government funded business advice for NFPs and start-ups | May 2004 - Dec 2006 | www.prevista.co.uk

Helped launch a number of successful businesses and Not-for-Profit organisations from the ground up securing government funding from the Access-2-Finance program. I built up a solid reputation for launching well planned and sustainable start up businesses/charities including Homeless Charities, Community Support/Mobility Groups, Community Training Programs, Subway Franchises and Pet Grooming services etc.

Education

University of Adelaide | 2020 - Current, Full-stack Web Development Bootcamp (part-time).

Brighton Business School | 2001 – 2002, Certificate in Management (Year 1 MBA). Subjects covered, economics, organisational behaviour, consumer psychology, operations management and accounting

Nottingham Trent University | 1990 – 1994, BA (Hons) Product Design.

St. Albans College of Art and Design | 1998 - 1990, BTEC National Diploma in Design (Distinction).

Sir Francis Bacon School | 1983 - 1998, St Albans, 6 GCSEs

.....

References (details provided on request)

Ben Reason - Founding Partner - Livework

Jonathon Warner - Director: The Brand Inside and ex HR Director: Xerox and Y&R (Europe)

Matt Lock - Matt Lock Associates